# Ilya Ivanenko

Email: <u>ivanenkoilya@gmail.com</u>

Cell: (650) 863-2547

#### **SUMMARY**

Completed four-year Computer Science university program in two and half years; graduated on the Dean's list. As a Software Development Engineer in Test, I have developed great teamwork, leadership, planning, and problem-solving skills with experience in leading a team in modern software development techniques such as Agile and User-centered design. Eager and quick to learn new skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Languages and Frameworks**

- Proficiency with C#, Java, C, C++, Python, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, and modern Web development technologies
- Experience with Android, git, XML, RESTful, Ruby, Prolog, Scheme, and Unix
- Working knowledge of Unity 3D, Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop, and Blender

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# **Employment Security Department, Washington State (Software Development Engineer in Test)**

August 2017 – Present

Lacey, WA

- Designed, developed, and maintained C# automation testing framework, significantly increasing efficiency throughout agency
- Created scripts and tools using C# and WPF to simplify and automate daily tester workflow
- Debugged through production code and database to make testing development practices stable, efficient, and flexible
- Introduced git best practices and mentored teammates about proper git usage and standards

## Lego Brand Retail (Sales Associate)

April 2015 - October 2016

San Mateo, CA

- Coordinated as a team to provide excellent customer service and keep store shelves full and organized
- Handled cash register transactions and returns
- Maintained and organized stockroom and offsite storage

#### **PROJECTS**

## **MyPlace Apartment Rental Site (Fall 2016)**

Project Technical Lead

https://github.com/IvanenkoIlya/MyPlace-CSc648-2016

- Worked with a team to design from the ground up a website where fellow students can search for and rent apartments. Actively used Agile Software Development techniques
- Employed multiple languages and tools including PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, and HTML to design the website using the Mini PHP framework
- Managed codebase and git repository
- Ensuring project stability for milestone releases
- Developed multiple features including user registration and login as well as search, filtering, and formatting results dynamically using AJAX
- Set up and tested deployment of web application from LAMP stack

## **EDUCATION**

## San Francisco State University (BS Computer Science)

June 2015 – December 2016

San Francisco, CA

## **College of San Mateo (AS Computer Science Application and Development)**

June 2012 - June 2015

San Mateo, CA

Java and C++ certifications